Register of the George D. Jenkins papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Subject File, 1893-1989 (Boxes 12-26, 39-40)
  - Trade, 1963 (Box-folder 25: 4)
  - United Muslim Party, 1953 (Box-folder 25: 5)
  - "Urbanization: Growth, Transitions and Problems of a Premier West African City (Lagos, Nigeria)," Patrick O. Ohadike, 1964 (Box-folder 40: 21)
  - "Urbanization: A Reading List,", 1965 (Box-folder 40: 22)
  - Used tax, 1958 (Box-folder 25: 6)
  - Violence, 1954-1957 (Box-folder 25: 7)
  - "Vote for Salawu Ajani, The Candidate of Northern People's Congress (NPC),", undated (Box-folder 25: 8)
  - Western House of Assembly debates, statements, and notes, 1953-1957 (Box-folder 25: 9)
  - Western Region, local government, estimates, 1956-1958 (Box-folder 25: 10-11)
  - Works, Town Planning and Tender (Road System and Water Connections), 1956-1957 (Box-folder 26: 1)
- Printed Matter, 1937-1989 (Boxes 26-28, 40-41)
  - Action Group of Nigeria, Democratic Socialism: Being the Manifesto, undated (Box-folder 26: 2)
  - Action Group of Nigeria, 1956 Summer School Lectures (Box-folder 26: 3)
  - Adebiyi, T. A., The Beloved Bishop: A Biography of Bishop A. B. Akinyele, 1969 (Box-folder 41: 5)
  - Adegoke, Adelabu, Africa in Ebullition: A Handbook for Freedom, 1952 (Box-folder 26: 5)
  - Administration of Physical Planning in Western Nigeria, 1967 (Box-folder 26: 4)
  - African Urban Notes, 1966 (Box-folder 40: 23)
  - African Urban Notes, 1967 (Box-folder 40: 24)
  - African Urban Notes, 1968 (Box-folder 41: 1)
  - African Urban Notes, 1969 (Box-folder 41: 2)
  - African Urban Notes, 1970 (Box-folder 41: 3)
  - Akinyele, Chief I. B., The Outlines of Ibadan History, 1946 (Box-folder 41: 8)
  - Authors’ Alterations Cost Money and Cause Delay..., 1960 (Box-folder 41: 4)
  - Center for Developing Area Studies, Manpower and Unemployment Research in Africa: A Newsletter, Vol. 1, no. 2; Vol. 2, no. 2; Vol. 3, nos. 1 and 2, 1968-1970 (Box-folder 26: 6-9)
  - Centre for Urban Studies, University College, London, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 41: 6)
  - Comments of the Federal Government on the Report of Coker Commission of Inquiry, 1962 (Box-folder 26: 10)
  - Constitution of the Action Group of Nigeria, 1962 (Box-folder 26: 11)
  - The Economic Bulletin of Ghana, 1966 (Box-folder 26: 13)
  - Federation of Nigeria, telephone directory, 1961 (Box-folder 26: 14)
  - "Fifth Annual Report of the Federal Loans Board, 1960-1961,", 1962 (Box-folder 26: 15)
  - "First Supplementary Estimates of the Government of the Federation of Nigeria, 1960-1961," (Box-folder 26: 16)
  - Government of Western Nigeria, telephone directory, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 27: 1)
  - Gugler, Jospeh, "Urbanization in Sub-saharan Africa," draft outline, 1969 (Box-folder 26: 12)
  - "Health and Wealth,", 1963 (Box-folder 27: 2)
  - How Nigeria Is Governed, undated (Box-folder 27: 3)
  - Ibadan City Council Estimates, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 27: 4)
  - Ibadan District Council Election, 1954 (Box-folder 27: 5)
  - Ibadan Grammar School: 1913-1963 Roll, undated (Box-folder 27: 6)
  - Ibadan Grammar School: 50th Anniversary Souvenir Handbook, 1913-1963 (Box-folder 27: 7)
  - Ibadan Livestock Rearing Industry Company (Nigeria) Ltd., "Memorandum and Articles,", undated (Box-folder 27: 8)
  - Iwe Itan Ibadan, 1959 (Box-folder 41: 7)
  - Iwe Itan Igbesi Aiye, 1958 (Box-folder 27: 9)
  - Lagos Town Council, 1961-1964
    - Accounts, 1961 (Box-folder 27: 12)
    - Estimates, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 27: 13)
    - Draft estimates, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 27: 14)
    - Estimates, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 27: 15)
  - "Local Government Circulars,", 1958 (Box-folder 27: 10)
  - "Local Government in the Western Provinces of Nigeria, 1939-1949,", 1950 (Box-folder 27: 11)
  - Mabogunje, Akin L., "Urbanization in Nigeria: A Constraint on Economic Development,", 1965 (Box-folder 41: 11)
  - Map of Departments and Offices, University College Ibadan, 1962 (Box-folder 27: 16)
  - The National Council of Nigeria and the Cameroons (NCNC), circa 1960 (Box-folder 27: 17)
  - Ni Iranti Eni Rere, undated (Box-folder 27: 18)
  - Nigeria Farmers Welfare Association, "Ofin Ati Eto Egbe,", undated (Box-folder 27: 19)
  - Oke-'badan: A Magazine of the Ibadan Students Union, Nigeria, 1962 (Box-folder 27: 20)
  - "The Petition of the Ibadan Native Authority to the Secretary of the State for the Colonies,", 1937 (Box-folder 27: 21)
  - "Physical Planning in the Western Nigeria,", 1966 (Box-folder 28: 1)
  - "Population Census of the Western Region of Nigeria,", 1952 (Box-folder 28: 2)
  - Press clippings, 1984-1989 (Box-folder 41: 9)
  - Report of the Commission of Inquiry into the Administration of the Ibadan District Council, 1956 (Box-folder 41: 10)
  - Report of the Special Study Mission to Africa, 1965 (Box-folder 28: 3)
  - Rural Africana, "Current Research in the Social Sciences, #6,", 1968 (Box-folder 28: 4)
  - Rural Africana, "Research Notes on Local Politics and Political Anthropology, #4,", 1968 (Box-folder 28: 5)
  - Trans-action, undated (Box-folder 28: 6)
  - Urbandoc Input Index, Cumulation 1, 1968 (Box-folder 28: 7)
  - Urbandoc Input Index, 3 and 4, 1968 (Box-folder 28: 8-9)
  - Urban Reserve News, 1969 (Box-folder 28: 10)
  - Western Nigeria Gazette, 1963 (Box-folder 28: 11)
  - Western Region Headquarters, telephone directory, 1959 (Box-folder 28: 12)
- Index Cards, 1960s (Boxes 29-30, 43)
  - Research notes covering the period 1908-1962 (Box 29)
  - Bibliography notes used for research (Box 30)
    Scope and Contents note
  - Chiefs and administrative files, 1965 (Box 43)
- Punch Cards, 1960s (Box 31, 42)
  - Notes on important personalities (Box-folder 31: 1)
  - Biographical I, 1965 (Box-folder 42: 3)
  - Biographical II, 1965 (Box-folder 42: 4)
  - Biographical III, 1965 (Box-folder 42: 5)
- Newspaper Clippings, 1945-1970 (Boxes 32-35)
  - Coker Commission, files 1 and 2, 1954-1963 (Box-folder 32: 1-2)
  - Dakar Matin, 1962 (Box-folder 32: 3)
  - Intellectuals - Aluko - sedition trial, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 32: 4)
  - Lagos, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 33: 1)
  - Local government, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 33: 2)
  - Treason trial of Awolowo, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 33: 3)
    See also Box 34, Folder 8 for additional treason trial clippings (September-December 1962).
  - Western Region, Nigeria, state of emergency, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 33: 4)
  - Various clippings, 1945-1962 (Box 34)
  - Various clippings, 1963, 1965, 1968-1970 (Box 35)
- Microfilm Reels, 1903-1962 (Reel 1-23)
  - Evolution of Ibadan, 1914-1956 (Reel 1)
  - Reorganization, Ibadan Town and District Administration, undated (Reel 1)
  - Intelligence Report on Ibadan, Ibadan Province, undated (Reel 1)
  - The Evolution of Ibadan, Captain C. H. Bigee, undated (Reel 1)
  - Ministry of Local Government Ibadan (Provisional), undated (Reel 1)
  - District Council Instruments, undated (Reel 1)
  - Petitions Concerning the Application of Local Government Law to Ibadan Division, Ibadan Province, undated (Reel 1)
  - The Petition of the Ibadan Native Authority, undated (Reel 1)
  - St. Peters Church, Aremo Ibadan, undated (Reel 1)
  - Intelligence Report on Ibadan Town by E. N. C. Dickinson, District Officer, undated (Reel 1)
  - Report of the General Re-organization of the Native Administration of Ibadan by I. W. E Dods, District Officer, undated (Reel 1)
  - London Constitutional Conference, 1957 (Reel 2)
  - National Council of Nigeria and the Cameroons (NCNC), undated (Reel 2)
  - Agenda and Minutes of Party Meetings, undated (Reel 2)
  - NCNC Finance, undated (Reel 2)
  - Western Region Election, 1956 (Reel 2)
  - NCNC Miscellaneous, undated (Reel 2)
  - NCNC Internal Papers, undated (Reel 2)
  - Meeting Notices, undated (Reel 2)
  - Steering and Plenary Session Minutes, undated (Reel 2)
  - Content Press Communique, undated (Reel 2)
  - Memoranda for Steering Committee, undated (Reel 2)
  - The Case for a Mid-West State, undated (Reel 2)
  - Forward to Freedom, undated (Reel 2)
  - Representation of the Ex-Servicemen Union Onitsha Division, undated (Reel 2)
  - Kalabari Petition on Self Government for Nigeria, undated (Reel 2)
  - United Muslim Party, undated (Reel 2)
  - Nigeria Constitutional Conference, 1957 (Reel 2)
  - Maiyegun Society Letter, 1949 May 8 (Reel 3)
  - Ishola, Are, Adebisi Letter of 28th March 1949 Supporting Laosun, undated (Reel 3)
  - M.S. Duty List, 1949 (Reel 3)
  - To Chairman and Executive of NCNC Last Time of Adelabu by an Organizing Secretary, undated (Reel 3)
  - Northern People's Congress (NPC) List of Executed Criminals Related to Adelabu Riots, undated (Reel 3)
  - Federal Election Campaign Release, 1959 (Reel 3)
  - Ibadan East Federal Returns, 1959 (Reel 3)
  - Ni Iranti Eni Rere, undated (Reel 3)
  - Ibadan Constituency Patriot Association, undated (Reel 3)
  - S. Lana Press Release on Expulsion of S. L. Akintola, undated (Reel 3)
  - NPC Appeal to Ibadan to Pay Taxes, 1962 (Reel 3)
  - Effon Alaye Chieftancy Matter, undated (Reel 3)
  - Ibadan People's Association, undated (Reel 3)
  - Report of Minister of Local Government to IDC, 1952 (Reel 3)
  - Application of Local Government Law to Ibadan, undated (Reel 3)
  - Ibadan Tax Payers Association, undated (Reel 3)
  - Ibadan Town Planning Authority, 1953 (Reel 3)
  - Agbaje Evidence, including Ibadan Progressive Union (IPU), Ibadan City Council (ICC), undated (Reel 3)
  - Goodwill Society, undated (Reel 3)
  - Tax Survey by Schofield, 1948 (Reel 3)
  - Reform Committee Minutes, undated (Reel 3)
  - Ibadan - Ife Boundary Dispute, 1932 (Reel 3)
  - Ibadan Oyo, 1936 (Reel 3)
  - Ibadan Natiae Settlers Union, The Works, 1950 (Reel 3)
  - African Club, undated (Reel 3)
  - Nigerian Civil Service Union, undated (Reel 3)
  - Ibadan Recreation Club, undated (Reel 3)
  - Tenants Union, undated (Reel 3)
  - Yoruba Students Union, undated (Reel 3)
  - Independent Schools Proprietors Association, undated (Reel 3)
  - IPU Study Circle, 1954 (Reel 3)
  - Union Club, undated (Reel 3)
  - Evening Collegiate Classes, Prospectus, undated (Reel 3)
  - Ibadan Old Grammarians Society, undated (Reel 3)
  - Letters, Correspondence, and Reports, 1937-1952 (Reel 4)
    - Nicholson, undated (Reel 4)
    - Resolution, undated (Reel 4)
    - Adelabu, undated (Reel 4)
    - United Africa Co. Ltd, undated (Reel 4)
    - African Staff, undated (Reel 4)
    - Agbaje, undated (Reel 4)
    - Institute of Social Science Ibadan, undated (Reel 4)
    - Royal Commission of Inquiry (NCNC), 1956 (Reel 4)
    - House of Assembly Debates, 1956 (Reel 4)
    - Deed of Partnership of the Ekiti Youth Transport Service (Adeleye Ajibade), undated (Reel 4)
    - Western Regional Production Development Board, Annual Report, 1954-1955 (Reel 4)
    - Inquiry into the Regional Government, 1956-1957 (Reel 4)
    - Nigeria Constitutional Conference, Yoruba Central State, Oyo Youth Vanguard, 1957 (Reel 4)
    - Justitia Fiat: Pamphlet Dedicated to Oba Alajyeluwa Adeniran Adeyj, undated (Reel 4)
  - Federal Minutes, undated (Reel 5)
  - Ibadan Politics, Some NCNC Materials, undated (Reel 5)
  - Northern Districts Reform, 1951-1957 (Reel 5)
  - Personal, undated (Reel 6)
  - Speeches and Releases, undated (Reel 6)
  - Ibadan Politics, undated (Reel 6)
  - Maiyegun Society, undated (Reel 7)
  - The Northern People's Congress (NPC), undated (Reel 7)
  - Capital Changes of Ibadan Riots, undated (Reel 7)
  - Eyi Ni Idi Mewa, undated (Reel 7)
  - Federal Election Campaign, Schedule of Total Valid Votes, undated (Reel 7)
  - Condition Permit, undated (Reel 7)
  - Ni Iranti Eni Rere, undated (Reel 7)
  - Ibadan Constituency Patriotic Association, undated (Reel 7)
  - NPC, undated (Reel 7)
  - Ibadan East District Council, undated (Reel 7)
  - Petition, undated (Reel 7)
  - Effon Alaye Chieftancy, undated (Reel 7)
  - Ibadan People's Association, undated (Reel 7)
  - Ibadan Tax Payers Association, undated (Reel 7)
  - Ibadan Town Planning Authority, undated (Reel 7)
  - Ibadan Progressive Union and Youth Group, undated (Reel 7)
  - Ibadan District Native Administration, undated (Reel 7)
  - Butcher's Commission of Enquiry, undated (Reel 7)
  - Ibadan Citizens Committee, undated (Reel 7)
  - Goodwill Society, undated (Reel 7)
  - Ibadan Citizens Council, undated (Reel 7)
  - Tax Survey in Ibadan, undated (Reel 7)
  - Water Works, undated (Reel 7)
  - Report Tax Collection, undated (Reel 7)
  - Report Committee of Enquiry, undated (Reel 7)
  - Nominal Roll, undated (Reel 7)
  - Ibadan Reform Committee, 1951 (Reel 7)
  - Report: Reform Sub-Committee, undated (Reel 7)
  - Ibadan Urbanization, undated (Reel 7)
  - Boundry, 1933 (Reel 7)
  - Ibadan Native Settlers Union, 1951 (Reel 7)
  - Land Policy Dispute, undated (Reel 7)
  - African Club, Ibadan, undated (Reel 7)
  - Boys Club, Ibadan, undated (Reel 7)
  - Tenants Union, undated (Reel 7)
  - Yoruba Students Union, undated (Reel 7)
  - Independent Schools, undated (Reel 7)
  - Education Dept, undated (Reel 7)
  - Senior Civil Servants, undated (Reel 7)
  - Ibadan Progressive Union (IPU), undated (Reel 7)
  - Ibadan Old Grammarians Society, undated (Reel 7)
  - Council Meetings, 1944-1945 (Reel 8)
  - Ibadan Native Administration, 1934 February 27 - 1937 August 10 (Reel 9)
  - Ibadan Native Administration Minutes Book, 1937 - 1941 November 22 (Reel 9)
  - 1935 16 - 1937 18, undated (Reel 10)
  - Diaries of Chief Obisesan, 1926-1930, 1932-1934 (Reel 11)
  - 1944 1 - 1951 8, undated (Reel 12)
  - Council Minutes, 1903 October 10 - 1905 May 13 (Reel 13)
  - Council Book, undated (Reel 13)
  - Ibadan Native Authority Minute Book, Vol. IV, 1924 April 7 - 1934 February 13 (Reel 13)
  - Section I: Local Government, Section II: Law, 1962 March 5 (Reel 14)
  - Northwestern University Comparative Program, 1962 April 10 (Reel 15)
  - Northwestern University Comparative Program (duplicate), 1962 April 10 (Reel 16)
  - Northwestern University Comparative Program (duplicate), 1962 April 10 (Reel 17)
  - Obisesan, 6 Volumes, 1938-1943 (Reel 18)
  - Ibadan Native Administration (INA) Council Minutes, 1945 August -1949 (Reel 19)
  - 1952 9 - 1960 18, undated (Reel 20)
  - 1914, 1920 2 - 1925 7, undated (Reel 21)
  - INA Council Minutes, 1941-1943 (Reel 22)
  - INA Council Minutes, 1944 January - 1944 October (Reel 22)
  - Ijoba Ibile Marun (3x duplicates), 1936 May 1 (Reel 23)
  - Ibadan Native Administration Chronicle, Vol. I, No. 1, 1934 November 1 (Reel 23)
  - Ijoba Ibile Marun, Vol. II, No. 16-18, 21, 22, 1936 May 1 - November 1 (Reel 23)
  - Ijoba Ibile Marun, Vol. III, No. 4-7, 1937 April 1 - July (Reel 23)
  - Ijoba Ibile Marun, Vol. I, No. 1, 1934 November 1 (Reel 23)
  - Ibadan N.A. Chronicle, Vol. I, No. 2-3, 1934 December 1 - 1935 January 1 (Reel 23)
  - Ijoba Ibile Marun, Vol. II, No.1-11, 13, 15, 17, 21-23, 1935 February 1 - 1936 December 11 (Reel 23)
  - Ijoba Ibile Marun, Vol. III, No. 1-2, 4-9, 11, 1937 January - November (Reel 23)
  - Itan Ijo Ibadan Ati Ti Adota Odun Ijo Yemetu, undated (Reel 23)
  - Lati Owo J. Latunji Dina, 1944 (Reel 23)
  - Dr. Edward Wilmot Blyden: An Interpretation. Julius Ojo-Cole, undated (Reel 23)
  - "In Truth and Justice" or "A Handbook of the Oyo Progressive Union Containing Historical Sketches of the Relationship between Oyo and Ibadan, Lagos,", 1938 (Reel 23)
  - Ijoba Ibile Marun, Vol. II, No.17, 1936 June 1 (Reel 23)
  - Wesley College List of Students, Methodist Missionary Society, 1905-1934 (Reel 23)
  - 2nd Delegation to Ibadan, 1952 May 10 (Reel 23)
  - Tour of the Honourable Minister for Local Government, Notes on the Meetings of the Ibadan Divisional Native Authority Held at Mapo Hall, 1952 June 3 (Reel 23)
  - The Application of the Local Government Law to Ibadan Town and District, undated (Reel 23)
  - Ibadan Tax Payers Association, Calling All Patriots!, undated (Reel 23)
  - Ibadan Town Planning Authority, 1953 May 1 (Reel 23)
  - Ibadan Town Planning Authority, 1953 May 6 (Reel 23)
  - Comments of the Ibadan Native Authority on the Query Raised by the President on the Selection of Persons Outside the Assembly to Serve in the Native Authority Committees, undated (Reel 23)
  - Ibadan Progressive Union, undated (Reel 23)
  - Statement Made by Mr. N.E. Whiting Senior District Officer, Ibadan, Before the Commission of Inquiry on Part (b) of the Terms of Reference, undated (Reel 23)
  - Evidence of the Ibadan Progressive Union, undated (Reel 23)
  - Evidence of the Ibadan District Native Administration Quarters Representatives before Butchers Commission of Enquiry into Allegations against Chief Salami Agbaje, the Otun Balogun of Ibadan and the Allegations of Mal-administration of the Affairs of the Ibadan and District Native Authority, undated (Reel 23)
  - An Extract of the Meeting of the Combined Advisory Condition Held on the 16th July 1949 at Mapo Hall, Administrative Secretary, undated (Reel 23)
  - Evidence of the Ibadan Progressive Union (Youth Gap) before the Butcher's Commission of Enquiry into the Allegations of Misconduct Made against Chief Salami Agbaje, the Otun Balogun of Ibadan, and the Allegation of Inefficiency, Mal-administration of the Affairs of the Ibadan and District Native Authority, undated (Reel 23)
  - Letter to H. L. Butcher, Esq, The Commissioner, Secretariat Ibadan from the Secretary Ibadan Citizens' Committee, c/o P.O. Box 153, Ibadan, undated (Reel 23)
  - Good-Will Society, undated (Reel 23)
  - Ibadan Native Authority Elections -1952 Election of Councillors Ballot Paper B, undated (Reel 23)
  - Ibadan Citizens' Council of the Egbe Omo Ibile Programme of Meetings, undated (Reel 23)
- Photographs, 1950-1965 (Box 42)
  - Adelabu, el al., 1950s (Box-folder 42: 1)
  - An aerial view, Ibadan, 1965 (Box-folder 42: 2)
- Maps, 1946-1965 (Box 44)
  - Map I: Africa, 1946
  - Map II: Ibadan and aerial view of Ibadan, 1950, 1965